A Guide to the Oscar M. Ruebhausen Papers FA077
Rockefeller Archive Center
Oscar M. Ruebhausen papers
1941-2000
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ruebhausen, Oscar M.
FA077
9 Cubic Feet 22 document cases
Arrangement note
For the most part, the files in this collection are arranged chronologically, based on the agency or committee with which Ruebhausen was working.
Biographical/Historical note
Oscar M. Ruebhausen was born in Manhattan on August 28, 1912, and grew up in Vermont. He graduated summa cum laude from Dartmouth in 1934 and in 1937 from Yale Law School, where he was a member of the Law Review. He then joined the law firm of Debevoise, Stevenson, Plimpton, & Page, a six-year-old firm with twelve lawyers that is now known as Debevoise Plimpton. Mr. Ruebhausen was presiding partner of Debevoise Plimpton from 1972 to 1981.
Exempt from military service for health reasons, he went to Washington, D.C. during World War II to work in the counsel's office of the Lend-Lease Administration. In 1944 he became general counsel for the Office of Scientific Research and Development, directed by Dr. Vannevar Bush.
Mr. Ruebhausen was an intimate but unpaid adviser to Nelson A. Rockefeller for many years and was active in various appointed positions in New York state government. He also managed Governor Rockefeller's properties in Venezuela and Ecuador. Additionally, he was chairman of the boards of the Russell Sage Foundation and the Greenwall Foundation. In the 1950s and 1960s, he was chairman of the board of Bennington College, where he made news by renouncing federal loans because students had to sign loyalty oaths to get them.
Oscar Ruebhausen died on December 7, 2004, in New York.
Scope and Contents note
This collection comprises a portion of the files of Oscar M. Ruebhausen (pronounced "REEB-how-zen"), an attorney and member of the Manhattan law firm of Debevoise Plimpton. Mr. Ruebhausen was a long-time friend and advisor to Nelson A. Rockefeller, whom he met in the late 1940s. While a small percentage of these records document his interactions with or about Governor Rockefeller, the bulk of the collection documents his professional activities outside of the law firm.
The collection begins with the personal files maintained by Mr. Ruebhausen while employed by the U. S. Office of Scientific Research and Development during World War II (folders 1-12). Next, there are materials related to the establishment of the National Science Foundation, for which he was an advisor (folders 17-21).
This collection also includes files concerning his work as the first Chair of the Association of the Bar of the City of New York's Committee on Atomic Energy, which was created shortly after World War II ended. This committee took the initiative in giving legal guidance to the U. S. Congress and the Atomic Energy Commission (folders 22-64). Of particular interest in his correspondence as Chair of the Bar Association Committee are letters and published papers reflecting his efforts to avoid secrecy in the workings of the AEC. The Bar Association Committee also prepared draft legislation for the creation of the New York State Office of Atomic Development in 1959, later called the New York State Office of Atomic and Space Development (folders 65-74). Mr. Ruebhausen was named Vice Chairman of this office by Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
Additionally, these papers contain extensive materials pertaining to his service as a member of the President's Science Advisory Committee during 1970-1972 (folders 82-92) and even more on fallout shelters from the 1950s and 1960s (folders 93-104). He was also very active in Governor Rockefeller's 1958 gubernatorial campaign as an officer of Democrats for Rockefeller (folders 106-116). Long a personal lawyer to Governor Rockefeller, he was instrumental in the 1983 creation of the Nelson A. Rockefeller Center for the Social Sciences at Dartmouth College, their mutual alma mater (folders 155-164).
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted are noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
File Plan
Former Classification: IV 3A 28
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
This collection was donated to the Rockefeller Archive Center in 2005.
Nuclear energy; Political campaigns -- United States; National Science Foundation. (U.S.); Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich)
- United States Office of Scientific Research and Development (OSRD) - Correspondence
  - May 11-August 11, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - August 29-October 31, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - November 1, 1944-January 15, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - January 16-March 31, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - April 1-May 31, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - June 1-August 31, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - September 1-December 6, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - December 11, 1945-January 31, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1945 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Scope and Contents note
    OSRD "Contract Manual" February 1, 1945 War and Navy Departments: "Explanation of Principles for Determination of Costs Under Government Contracts"
- United States Office of Scientific Research and Development (OSRD) Contracts Forms Manual, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- United States Office of Scientific Research and Development (OSRD), 1941 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Ruebhausen Desk Reference Book (Part I): OSRD Executive Orders, administrative orders, forms, subcontracts, purchase agreement, penicillin contracts (declassified), insurance
- United States Office of Scientific Research and Development (OSRD), 1941 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Ruebhausen Desk Reference Book (Part II): Lend-Lease, OSRD Executive Orders, overhead, cost-plus, travel, legislation, contract form, property transfer form, patents, memo of law
- Lend-Lease Administration, 1941-1943 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Report to the President on operations by director Edward R. Stettinius, Jr.
- Powers of the Foreign Economic Administration, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Summary of pertinent legislation, Executive Orders
- International Development, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  Manual of legislation, Executive Orders, foreign economic administration, Administration for Economic Development, Technical Corporation Administration (TCA), Point IV Agreement with Ceylon, Organization of TCA
- International Development Advisory Board, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  Point IV manual, investment guaranty handbook
- National Science Foundation
  - 1945 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Legislative proposals and hearings
  - 1945-1952 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Reports, legislation
  - 1948-1951 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Correspondence and memoranda
  - 1947 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - 1946 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Atomic Energy Commission - Association of the Bar of the City of New York (ABCNY) - Correspondence
  - 1949 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - 1950 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - 1951 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - January-March 1952 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - April-May 1952 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - June-September 1952 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - October 1952 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - November-December 1952 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - January-March 1953 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - April-May 1953 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - June-August 1953 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - September-October 1953 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - November-December 1953 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - January-June 1954 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - July-December 1954 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - January-June 1955 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - July-December 1955 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - January 2-May 22, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - May 23-December 30, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - 1957 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - 1958 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - 1959 (Box 8, Folder 43)
- Atomic Energy Commission - Association of the Bar of the City of New York (ABCNY) - International Correspondence, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 44)
- Atomic Energy Commission - Association of the Bar of the City of New York (ABCNY) - International Correspondence, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 45)
- Atomic Energy Commission - Association of the Bar of the City of New York (ABCNY) - International Correspondence and Addresses, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 46)
- Atomic Energy Commission - Association of the Bar of the City of New York (ABCNY) - Special Committee Minutes, 1953-1959 (Box 8, Folder 47)
- Atomic Energy Tax Exemption, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  Memos and correspondence
- Association of the Bar of the City of New York, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  Round Table Conference invitation to Oscar M. Ruebhausen and reply
- "Harvard Law Review" Article, June 1953 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  Correspondence on "The Atomic Energy Act and Private Production of Atomic Power," by Oscar M. Ruebhausen and Robert von Murhens.
- Atomic Energy Commission - Association of the Bar of the City of New York (ABCNY), 1952-1959 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  Annual reports, 1952-1959 Annual report to Rockefeller Foundation, 1952-1953
- Atomic Energy - Atomic Suspense and Information, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  Control, letter to Oscar M. Ruebhausen signed by Senator Hubert H. Humphrey of the Committee on Government Operations.
- Atomic Energy - Proposed New York State Legislation, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  Proposed Atomic Energy Law, letter from Oscar M. Ruebhausen to Jonathan Bingham, Secretary to Governor Harriman.
- Atomic Energy Commission - Association of the Bar of the City of New York (ABCNY), 1956 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  Special Report -- Atomic Energy in United Kingdom, Canada, and Australia
- Atomic Energy Commission - Association of the Bar of the City of New York (ABCNY), 1956 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  Draft of "Atomic Insurance Problem," May 21, 1956
- Atomic Energy Commission - Association of the Bar of the City of New York (ABCNY), 1953 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  Atomic energy and bar associations
- Atomic Energy Commission - Association of the Bar of the City of New York (ABCNY), 1952, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  "Effects of an Atomic Attack upon the Legal Structure"
- Atomic Energy Commission - Association of the Bar of the City of New York (ABCNY), 1958 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  Atomic inspection, Council on Foreign Relations, "Peaceful Uses of Atomic Energy"
- Atomic Energy Commission - Association of the Bar of the City of New York (ABCNY), 1950-1953 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  Interim reports
- Atomic Energy Commission - Association of the Bar of the City of New York (ABCNY), 1954 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  Draft statement of position, May 2, 1954
- Atomic Energy Commission - Association of the Bar of the City of New York (ABCNY), 1950-1951 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  Rockefeller Foundation, grant-in-aid, correspondence
- Atomic Energy Commission - Association of the Bar of the City of New York (ABCNY), 1953-1957 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  Speeches and articles
- Atomic Energy Commission - Association of the Bar of the City of New York (ABCNY), 1949-1955 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  Oscar M. Ruebhausen statements on atomic energy
- Atomic Energy Commission - Association of the Bar of the City of New York (ABCNY), 1951-1952 (Box 10, Folder 64)
  "Corporate Law and the Atom," incomplete civil defense paper by Oscar M. Ruebhausen, March 4, 1952; correspondence; bills
- New York State Atomic Research & Development Authority (NYSARDA) - Annual Reports, 1963-1974 (Box 10, Folder 65)
- New York State Atomic Research & Development Authority (NYSARDA), 1963 (Box 10, Folder 66)
  Lease, facilities contract, and waste storage agreement with Nuclear Fuel Services, Inc.
- New York State Atomic Research & Space Development Authority, 1967-1978 (Box 10, Folder 67)
  Previously New York State Atomic Research & Development Authority (NYSARDA). Correspondence, statutes, by-laws.
- Atomic Energy Study (Envelope III), 1949-1950 (Box 10, Folder 68)
  Fellowships and Hanford overrun, congressional hearings
- Atomic Energy Study (Envelope III), 1948 (Box 11, Folder 69)
  Labor
- Atomic Energy Study (Envelope III), 1948 (Box 11, Folder 70)
  Natural gas pipeline
- Atomic Energy Study (Envelope III), 1950-1951 (Box 11, Folder 71)
  Radioisotopes
- Atomic Energy Study (Envelope IV), 1950 (Box 11, Folder 72)
  National Science Foundation
- Atomic Energy Study (Envelope IV), 1950 (Box 11, Folder 73)
- Atomic Energy Act of 1946 and Amendments (Box 11, Folder 74)
- Health, Education, and Welfare, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 75)
  Task Force on Prescription Drugs
- Health, Education, and Welfare, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 76)
  Second report on oral contraceptives
- National Academy of Sciences, 1959, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 77)
  1.) Carcinogens in food additives, 1959 2.) Chemicals used in food processing, 1965
- Water Pollution and Clean Air, 1969-1971 (Box 12, Folder 78)
  Reports and legislation
- Pesticides and Herbicides, 1969-1971 (Box 12, Folder 79)
  Reports
- Federal Food, Drug and Cosmetic Act, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 80)
  Legislation, report, adverse reactions reporting systems
- Drugs - Efficacy and Safety, 1970-1971 (Box 12, Folder 81)
  Decision making, quality of advice, reports by Interdisciplinary Communications Associates, Inc.
- President's Science Advisory Committee (PSAC), 1972 (Box 13, Folder 82)
  Panel on Chemicals and Health (PCH) -- miscellaneous background papers, regulatory decision making, drafts, opinions, reports, articles
- President's Science Advisory Committee (PSAC), 1972 (Box 13, Folder 83)
  Panel on Chemicals and Health (PCH) -- miscellaneous background papers
- President's Science Advisory Committee (PSAC), 1971 (Box 13, Folder 84)
  Panel on Chemicals and Health (PCH) -- miscellaneous
- President's Science Advisory Committee (PSAC), 1971 (Box 13, Folder 85)
  Panel on Chemicals and Health (PCH) -- spreadsheets, regulatory calendar, "New Yorker" article, "The Enigmatic Enzyme"
- President's Science Advisory Committee (PSAC), 1965-1970 (Box 13, Folder 86)
  Panel on Chemicals and Health (PCH) -- Miscellaneous
- President's Science Advisory Committee (PSAC), 1972; Folder 1 of 4 (Box 14, Folder 87)
  Panel on Chemicals and Health (PCH) -- draft report
- President's Science Advisory Committee (PSAC), 1972; Folder 2 of 4 (Box 14, Folder 88)
- President's Science Advisory Committee (PSAC), 1972; Folder 3 of 4 (Box 14, Folder 89)
- President's Science Advisory Committee (PSAC), 1972; Folder 4 of 4 (Box 14, Folder 90)
- Administrative Conference of the United States, ca. 1972 (Box 14, Folder 91)
  Rulemaking report by the Food and Drug Administration.
- Drug Assessment, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 92)
  Conference on philosophy and technology
- Fallout Shelters - Hudson Institute, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 93)
  Arms Control & Civil Defense: 1) The question of Crisis Evaluation 2) Civil Defense & Arms Control Objectives 3) Civil Defense Programs in the Present World 4) The Domestic Political Interactions
- Fallout Shelters - Hudson Institute, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 94)
  A reappraisal of nonmilitary defense policies, final report: Volumes I and II
- Fallout Shelters - Hudson Institute, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 95)
  Nonmilitary defense policies: A Context Reappraisal and Commentary, Volumes I and II
- Fallout Shelters, 1961-1963 (Box 15, Folder 96)
  Congressional reports and hearings
- Fallout Shelters - Pamphlets, Reports, 1958-1967 (Box 15, Folder 97)
- Fallout Shelters - Pamphlets, Reports, 1958-1967 (Box 15, Folder 98)
  Pamphlet by Oscar M. Ruebhausen "Fallout Shelters and Survival" (1962)
- Fallout Shelters, 1958-1961 (Box 15, Folder 99)
  Miscellaneous memos and pamphlets
- Fallout Shelters, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 100)
  "Nuclear Survival" -- resource handbook by New York State Education Department, reorganization of New York Civil Defense Commission
- Fallout Shelters, 1962-1964 (Box 16, Folder 101)
  "Effective Civil Defense" by Harvard Business School "Arms Control and Civil Defense" by Hudson Institute
- Fallout Shelter Clippings, 1959, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 102)
  "New York Times" profile of Oscar M. Ruebhausen, 1959 Task force report to Nelson Rockefeller on fallout shelters Transcript of program "The Open Mind," with Oscar M. Ruebhausen a participant, from NBC television, November 12, 1961
- Memorabilia - Fallout, 1965-1983 (Box 16, Folder 103)
  Photographs, Atomic Industrial Forum
- Memorabilia, 1961-1962 (Box 16, Folder 104)
  "Fallout Shelters and Survival" -- paper by Oscar M. Ruebhausen reprinted from "The Record of the Association of the Bar of the City of New York," January 1962.
- Memorabilia, 1951 (Box 16, Folder 105)
  "Partners in Progress" report to President Harry Truman
- Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Campaign, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 106)
  Democrats for Rockefeller Committee, miscellaneous campaign literature, memos on formation of committee, copies of letters to Nelson A. Rockefeller from Franklin D. Roosevelt (March 31, 1945) and Harry Truman (March 9, 1951 and November 5, 1951), memos on formation and organization of committee.
- Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Campaign, 1958-1959 (Box 16, Folder 107)
  Democrats for Rockefeller Committee, miscellaneous correspondence
- Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Campaign, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 108)
  Democrats for Rockefeller Committee -- basic campaign material
- Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Campaign, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 109)
  Democrats for Rockefeller Committee -- legal and financial, list of contributions
- Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Campaign, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 110)
  Democrats for Rockefeller Committee -- committee members and volunteers
- Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Campaign, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 111)
  Democrats for Rockefeller Committee -- administration
- Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Campaign, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 112)
  Democrats for Rockefeller Committee -- final reports and recommendations, "New York Times" and "New York Herald Tribune" results
- Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Campaign, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 113)
  Democrats for Rockefeller Committee -- letters of appreciation
- Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Campaign, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 114)
  Democrats for Rockefeller Committee -- ideas, suggestions, creations not used
- Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Campaign, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 115)
  Democrats for Rockefeller Committee -- lists, possible committee names
- Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Campaign, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 116)
  Democrats for Rockefeller Committee -- "Meet Nelson Rockefeller," booklet by New York State Republican Committee, ads, clippings
- Memorabilia, 1959-1962 (Box 17, Folder 117)
  Political correspondence including handwritten letter to Oscar M. Ruebhausen from Henry Kissinger, c. 1960.
- Memorabilia - 1962 Gubernatorial Campaign (Box 17, Folder 118)
  People for Rockefeller campaign, correspondence, "New York Post" ad, treasurer's report from Democrats for Rockefeller, New York Secretary of State filing and reports, members and contributions.
- Memorabilia - 1970 Gubernatorial Campaign (Box 17, Folder 119)
  Democrats for Rockefeller, campaign ads, bumper sticker, press releases.
- International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC), 1973 (Box 18, Folder 120)
  Miscellaneous correspondence Oscar M. Ruebhausen resignation as a director
- International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC), 1968-1976 (Box 18, Folder 121)
  Deferred compensation of Oscar M. Ruebhausen
- Insurance Holding Company Study, 1967-1968 (Box 18, Folder 122)
  Correspondence, press releases
- Insurance Holding Company Study, 1969-1974 (Box 18, Folder 123)
  Correspondence
- Council for Advancement of Legal Education, 1968-1972 (Box 18, Folder 124)
- Memorabilia, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 125)
  National Science Foundation: Presentation to Oscar M. Ruebhausen of Franklin D. Roosevelt letters
- Memorabilia, 1939 (Box 18, Folder 126)
  Oscar M. Ruebhausen's certificate of admission to practice before the Interstate Commerce Commission
- Memorabilia, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 127)
  "Nucleonics" magazine issue
- Memorabilia - United States Government, ca. 1943 (Box 18, Folder 128)
  Letter to Adlai Stevenson, Special Assistant, Office of the Secretary of the Navy from Francis Plimpton recommending Oscar M. Ruebhausen for position.
- Memorabilia - United States Government, 1942-1946 (Box 18, Folder 129)
  Oscar M. Ruebhausen employment records
- Memorabilia - United States Government, 1946-1975 (Box 18, Folder 130)
  Office of Scientific Research and Development (OSRD) news clippings, Oscar M. Ruebhausen citation
- Memorabilia - United States Government, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 131)
  Office of Scientific Research and Development (OSRD): "Science," 'The Endless Frontier'
- Memorabilia - United States Government, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 132)
  Commendation letter to Oscar M. Ruebhausen signed by Richard M. Nixon
- Memorabilia - United States Government, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 133)
  White House dinner invitation
- Memorabilia - State of New York, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 134)
  Oscar M. Ruebhausen appointment as Special Advisor on Atomic Energy
- Memorabilia - State of New York, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 135)
  Oscar M. Ruebhausen civil defense commendation
- Memorabilia - State of New York, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 136)
  Oscar M. Ruebhausen Certificate of Admission to Practice, New York State Court of Appeals
- Memorabilia - State of New York, 1959-1961 (Box 18, Folder 137)
  Miscellaneous documents on Advisory Committee on Atomic Energy
- Memorabilia - State of New York, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 138)
  Report of Special Committee on Insurance Holding Companies
- Memorabilia - State of New York, 1970, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 139)
  Nelson A. Rockefeller (signed) thank-you letters to Oscar M. Ruebhausen
- Memorabilia - State of New York, 1959, 1969, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 140)
  Photos
- Memorabilia - State of New York, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 141)
  Certificate of Outstanding Public Service to State of New York
- Memorabilia - State of New York, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 142)
  United Nations Day proclamation
- Memorabilia - State of New York, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 143)
  Citation from National Institute for Disaster Mobilization
- Memorabilia - State of New York, 1971-1974 (Box 18, Folder 144)
  News clippings on trust created for benefit of Oscar M. Ruebhausen by Governor Rockefeller
- Memorabilia - State of New York, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 145)
  "Town & Country" January issue, "Nelson Rockefeller, Art Merchant"
- Memorabilia - Atomic Energy - Papers by Oscar M. Ruebhausen, 1950-1953 (Box 19, Folder 146)
  "Amend the Atomic Energy Act?" (c. 1953) "Atomic Attack and the Legal Situation," Association of the Bar of the City of New York (1952) "The Atomic Energy Act and the Private Production of Atomic Power," "Harvard Law Review," June 1953
- Memorabilia - Atomic Energy - Papers by Oscar M. Ruebhausen, 1950, 1955 (Box 19, Folder 147)
  1) Atomic Energy--Its International Aspects 2) "Changes in the Atomic Energy Act"
- Memorabilia - Atomic Energy - Paper by Oscar M. Ruebhausen, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 148)
  "Industrializing the Atom"
- Memorabilia - Atomic Energy - Paper by Oscar M. Ruebhausen, 1954 (Box 19, Folder 149)
  "New Atomic Problems"
- Memorabilia - Atomic Energy - Paper by Oscar M. Ruebhausen, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 150)
  "Possible Changes in the Atomic Energy Act"
- Memorabilia - Atomic Energy, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 151)
  Three pamphlets attributed to Governor Rockefeller: 1) Survival in a Nuclear Attack 2) No Test Ban Now 3) Power to Save Freedom
- Memorabilia - Atomic Energy - Paper by Oscar M. Ruebhausen, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 152)
  "Towards a New Atomic Policy"
- Memorabilia - Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 153)
  Oscar M. Ruebhausen memo re: tour of Kykuit
- Nelson A. Rockefeller Institute of Government at State University of New York (SUNY), 1984-1986 (Box 19, Folder 154)
  Endowment campaign
- Dartmouth College
  Scope and Contents
  Nelson A. Rockefeller Center for the Social Sciences correspondence
  - 1983 (Box 19, Folder 155)
  - 1984 (Box 19, Folder 156)
  - 1985 (Box 19, Folder 157)
  - 1986-1987 (Box 19, Folder 158)
  - January-August 1988 (Box 20, Folder 159)
  - September-October 1988 (Box 20, Folder 160)
  - 1989 (Box 20, Folder 161)
  - 1990 (Box 20, Folder 162)